<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>soil taxonomy on humus.rocks - soil is life on the rocks</title>
    <link>/tags/soil-taxonomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in soil taxonomy on humus.rocks - soil is life on the rocks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/soil-taxonomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Soil Taxonomy Graph Database with Neo4j and Cypher</title>
      <link>/post/2020/08/22/soil-taxonomy-graph-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/08/22/soil-taxonomy-graph-database/</guid>
      <description>For several years I have dreamt of ontologies and directed graph structures for representation of the logic in Soil Taxonomy. The express purpose of such work is that computer-aided taxonomy is “easier,” less prone to error, and enables more powerful reasoning about inherently abstract – but reasonably well-defined – concepts.
As an undergraduate in Dr. Schulthess’ soils classes at UCONN – the “graphy-ness” of Soil Taxonomy became apparent to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimations of Soil Depth with aqp</title>
      <link>/post/2020/07/13/estimations-with-algorithms-for-quantitative-pedology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/07/13/estimations-with-algorithms-for-quantitative-pedology/</guid>
      <description>Estimation of soil depth in aqp R package Estimation functions for soils try to calculate unknown properties based on existing observations and known relationships. The term pedotransfer function was coined by Johan Bouma as “translating data we have into what we need.” Soil surveys, and especially the primary descriptions collected by field soil scientists, offer many opportunities for leveraging this type of information.
In Algorithms for Quantitative Pedology aqp, the heuristics are defined in terms of R code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claves para la Taxonomía del Suelos</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/23/claves-para-la-taxonomia-kstlookup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/23/claves-para-la-taxonomia-kstlookup/</guid>
      <description>Buscar Criterios de Taxón La Taxonomía del Suelo es un idioma utilizado en todo el mundo.
Hice que mi algoritmo funcionara con las Claves españolas. ¡Echale un vistazo!
https://brownag.shinyapps.io/KSTLookup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Soil Taxonomy Preceding Taxa App</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/13/soil-taxonomy-preceding-taxa-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/13/soil-taxonomy-preceding-taxa-app/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on my work with the underlying structure and logic of Soil Taxonomy, I have created another derivative of my text-mined database.
https://brownag.shinyapps.io/KSTPreceding/
This Shiny app shows all taxa that precede the specified taxon in the classification “sequence” specified by the Keys to Soil Taxonomy.
This type of visualization is very relevant to the logic of the Keys, because in some ways, taxa are as much what they are, as what they are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Soil Taxonomy Taxon Criteria App</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/10/soil-taxonomy-taxon-criteria-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/10/soil-taxonomy-taxon-criteria-app/</guid>
      <description>Here is a basic Shiny app interface to a new database I developed from performing text mining analyses on the Keys to Soil Taxonomy (12th edition). This is alpha version of the “KSTLookup” Shiny app – a new tool for viewing criteria associated with taxa at the subgroup to order level in U.S. Soil Taxonomy.
https://brownag.shinyapps.io/KSTLookup/
Enter a taxon name such as “Spodosols”, “Aeric Endoaquepts”, “Glacistels” and see the tree of criteria – essentially a “pathway” leading to that specific taxon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mollic epipedon thickness requirement</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/30/mollic-epipedon-thickness-requirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/30/mollic-epipedon-thickness-requirement/</guid>
      <description>[This functionality has been live in aqp since version 1.21+]
Here is a demonstration of some new functionality I am working on for evaluating taxonomic criteria with aqp.
mollic.thickness.requirement calculates the minimum thickness of the materials meeting other requirements for a mollic epipedon, per criterion 6 in U.S. Soil Taxonomy (12th edition). I have used it for QC of pedon data, and also to assess questions about how frequently e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>